Christine Wangui.

Full Stack Web Developer.

Solution-Driven Full Stack Developer well versed in both front-end and back-end coding. Expert in handling the full software development lifecycle with focus on quality, security, and usability of customer-focused websites and mobile applications. I bring great multitasking and problem-solving abilities combined with advanced JavaScript, React.JS and Node.JS coding skills.



wanguiwamutitu@gmail.com 0799352229

Nairobi, Kenya.

Education

Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology (JKUAT), Bachelor of Science (BSc), Mathematics and Computer Science, $2017 \sim 2021$

Activities and societies.

- i) A member of the Rotaract Club of JKUAT. I served on the Public Relations committee where I learnt how to design and make posters using Figma and Canva. I also was in the Professional and Leadership development team where I gained skills in leading teams and how to help people grow professionally.
- ii) A member of Google Developers Students Club in the Web Development cohort. I learnt how to work with other developers in developing team projects.
- iii) A member of Gavel Club, an affiliate of Toastmaster's International. I was able to learn and grow my public speaking skills. iv) I specialized in Statistics as my Mathematics option. I was able to pick up relevant skills in Data Analysis and Modeling using R and SPSS.
- Kabare Girls' High School (A-), High School Diploma, 2013 ~ 2016.

Work Experience

Upwork, FrontEnd Web Developer Freelancer, Jun 2021 ~ Present.

I currently work as a web developer freelancer in Upwork.

I majorly work in developing websites and/or improving exsiting websites.

IEBC kenya, IEBC Enumerator, Aug 2019 ~ Aug 2019

I was involved in the 2019 census training and enumeration process as an enumerator. I was assigned a location to carry out the enumeration. I carried out the process effectively in three days.

Skills

Front-End.

JavaScript (React.JS and React Native), HTML, CSS (Bootstrap and SASS). Design using Flgma.

Back-end.

Node.JS, Express, MongoDB, PHP, MySQL, Firebase.

Soft Skills.

Teamwork, Public Speaking, Analytical Thinking.

Projects

Kejani App.

I lead a team of five in making a rental app that helps tenants connect with landlords with available homes. Technologies used: React.JS and Firebase.

Link: https://rental-app-c8057.web.app/

For more projects check out my porfolio.

Movies App.

A movies app where you get to view your latest movies and series. Technologies:React.Js, IMDb API and CSS3. Link: https://movies-72dc9.web.app/

Community Service.

Apr 2018 - Present

I participate in many community service activities through the Rotaract Club of JKUAT such as tree planting, visiting children's homes and community cleaning services.

I participate in mentoring pupils in primary schools interested in technology.

Powered by CakeResume